http://www.iawp.org/privacy

Disclosure and Terms of Service
Introduction The International Association of Women Police (IAWP) respects each individual’s right to personal privacy. We will collect and use information in the ways disclosed through this statement. This statement applies to IAWP applications for membership or registration for training or items IAWP may offer when it collects and maintains information (data) on you. IAWP does not share or sell your membership status, contact information or email address with anyone (unless ordered to provide the information to a court of competent jurisdiction). In addition, IAWP will not use your contact information to solicit you commercially, ask for contributions for individuals/ groups/ organizations, or generate/respond to queries which are from outside parties, or for any other similar activities that are not directly IAWP operation related or are not specifically approved by the President or the Board of Directors for distribution or publication to members. The website may collect general statistical information involuntarily from website visitors to determine statistics (page hits). IAWP adheres to the principles of Privacy by Design concept, Right to be Forgotten, and Data Erasure.
What personal information do we collect? Personal data is defined as any information to a natural person or “data subject” that can be used to directly or indirectly identify a person.  Covered items include a name, photo, email address, bank details, post on social networking websites, medical information and a computer IP address.  The IAWP collects and maintains your name, email and mailing addresses, telephone, and work information which is stored in the membership database. We collect information from you when you respond to a survey or fill out a form. Data we request that is not required will be specified as voluntary or optional.
What do we use your information for? Any of the information we collect from you may be used to improve our website by learning which pages are visited most often; to improve service to more effectively respond to your requests; to process monetary and financial transactions; to send periodic emails; to administer a contest, promotion, voting, poll, survey, or other site features. Occasionally, we may pass on to you a request from a Police Department to voluntarily provide information or participate in a survey when we determine the project is likely to further the interest of IAWP or women police globally.  The response is voluntary on your part and you determine the appropriateness of providing personal details or information on your Department to that requestor in accordance with your personal or police force's guidelines.  We may make the requests under our Member Broadcast Service or through a special link on the website. (IAWP always reserves its right to refuse participation entirely; there is no appeal to our decision.)
Your IAWP information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever.  The email address you provide may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to the organization, its conferences and training, membership news, organization news, member promotions, product or service information, for examples.  Note: If at any time you want to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include an unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email and you may also make a request to IAWP to unsubscribe you from emails.
Who has access to member data? A “data controller” means the IAWP organization with ‘control’ over membership  data.  A “data processor” means the IAWP official(s) who has access to and processes member data on behalf of the IAWP.  There are two officials who are data processors for IAWP membership: The Treasurer and the Membership Manager. IAWP may also give limited access to processors to  manage registrations for conferences.
What is the IAWP process in case of a data breach? If a data breach occurs, the service provider (Wild Apricot, PayPal are two examples) will notify IAWP (data controller) which will notify IAWP members within 72 hours of first having become aware of the breach.  The IAWP will provide as much detail as is authorized for release to impacted members. The data processor(s) will respond to requests from individual members for information and assistance which can be provided under the circumstances.
What is the Minimum amount of data required by IAWP for membership? In fact, the only data that is mandatory with IAWP for a membership in IAWP is full name, organization, country, title/rank, and email address.  On the other hand, for example, in order to deliver the magazine in print, your mailing address is necessary so that IAWP can comply with your request for delivery.  The “minimum” data requirement is also known as the “Privacy by Design” concept.  IAWP adheres to this concept.
Can I request that my data be deleted? Members have the right to have their data deleted entirely from IAWP’s database when forfeiting their membership.  A forfeiture occurs automatically upon non-renewal of dues or at any time upon the request of a member.  Non-renewals or incomplete member applications are moved into data archives.  A request for deletion can be given to any IAWP Official and/or Regional Coordinator who will arrange for the record deletion.  This right is known as “Right to be Forgotten” and “Data Erasure.”
How do we protect your information? We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. These security measures include: restricting access to member records; password protecting pages, directories and databases to safeguard your information from outside view;  and adding SSL (Secure Sockets Layered) technology to encrypt web page information sent across the Internet.
We offer the use of a third-party providers such as PayPal for financial transaction processing. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via financial encryption technology as required by U.S. banking regulations. No one in our organization can access your card details or purchase information or data. Third-party providers maintain their own set of privacy policies; we encourage you to check them for details.
Do we disclose any information to outside parties? We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your membership status, email, address, or any personally identifiable information. This does not include IAWP authorized individuals managing member records or trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. (An example would be the company who mails the magazines has access to your name and postal mailing address.)
We may release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. (An example would be page hit statistics which are only numbers of hits to a webpage.)
Third party links At our discretion, we may include or offer outside products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.
Copyright and Trademark Notice All IAWP (International Association of Women Police) trademarks, logos, service marks, trade dress, slogans, copyrighted designs or other brand features (collectively "Brand Features") will be used only as explicitly licensed by the International Association of Women Police (IAWP), and only under the terms and conditions and for the purposes described if such License is issued to outside parties. No reproduction or duplication, in whole or in part, of any section, item, text or graphics found on this Website is authorized unless a grant of License or Copyright Permission is specifically issued in writing. The IAWP Website is copyrighted and protected in full by international law as is the material and content therein protected by the IAWP. If there is a question on our Licensing Guidelines, Copyrights, or if you have a Permission Request, you may email the President and the Executive Director of the IAWP.  Details are at this webpage, trademarks-copyrights.htm.
Membership Directory Member Privacy Guidelines The IAWP Member Privacy Guidelines for the Member Directory protects IAWP Member contact details from disclosure without the member’s consent.
The guideline is simple:  No member may make available for personal, bulk or public use the details on any other member without the member’s consent for the disclosure.  This also prohibits members from soliciting other members using the contact details found in the Directory. (See also IAWP Policy 13 IAWP Internet Resources, Paragraph 7, Privacy Policy and Access to IAWP Member Directory.)
Background:  The new Members Only system contains a web-based directory of worldwide members intended for IAWP Member’s use in networking with colleagues.  The directory offers information which may includes email, telephone and postal addresses.  Misuse of IAWP Member information may cause a suspension/ban on membership with the organization and may also serve as legal ground if the violation of a Member's right to privacy is pursued through a court.
At the heart of the guideline is that Members shall not reveal information in IAWP records to outside or unauthorized individuals.  Out of fairness to all Members, information is protected information under United States and other country privacy and spam regulations to prohibit disclosure of member details to outside parties, unless authorized by a court.  The IAWP does not authorize disclosure of its directory.
Your Consent By using our site, applying to our organization, or accessing links, you consent to our privacy policy.
Future Changes We will post changes on this page, and/or update the modification date below. Changes will apply only to information collected after the date of the change.Contacting Us If there are any questions you may contact us using the information below.
Board information at www.iawp.org Mailing information
International Association of Women Police
12600 Kavanaugh Lane
Bowie, Maryland 20715
USA
Email: iawp@iawp.org
Telephone: +1 302-464-1402 or +1 301-805-0784
Pledge We pledge to you that we have made a dedicated effort to be in line with important laws and initiatives.
This policy is consistent with the US Federal Trade Commission Fair Information Practices.
This policy is consistent with the California US Online Privacy Protection Act.
This policy is consistent with the US Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.
This policy is consistent with the International Digital Privacy Alliance guidelines.
This policy is consistent with the CAN-SPAM Act. (Controlling the Assault of Non-Solicited Pornography And Marketing Act of 2003).
This policy is consistent with the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
This policy is consistent with guidelines and best practices for website disclosure to its site visitors.
Respectfully,
Copyrighted 2018 IAWP.
IAWP is a 501(c)6 non-profit organization founded in 1915 and is unique being the oldest organization for women in policing.
Powered by Wild Apricot Membership Software
